Cedric Hata

Summary

As an **innovative Software Engineer**, I built products for web and mobile app users **over 6+ years**, meeting the highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, and speed. I bring a strong commitment to collaboration and have an excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction.

As an active man, I love sports especially Football, Boxing, and Volleyball.

Work History

Full Stack Engineer / Thought Media (Remote / New York)

MAR 2019 - PRESENT

- Work with a team of web designers, back-end developers, and QAs to meet **project goals** and create effective **user experiences** with digital products to increase productivity by 33%.
- Developed full-stack applications across various platforms using the latest industry-adopted technologies and frameworks including React, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Django, Firebase Store, MySQL, and AWS, etc.
- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Worked on the **Agile** methodology and followed **Scrum** in many projects.
- Tech Stack: React, Tailwind CSS, TypeScript, Django, Firebase, MySQL, AWS

Full Stack Developer / Kaizo (Amsterdam)

NOV 2016 - FEB 2019

- Developed **dynamic** and **interactive** websites that ensured high traffic, page views, and user experience, resulting in 40% increase in sales revenue.
- Added to the company database of code by developing reusable code that could minimize the time needed to complete projects in the future.
- Oversaw **full lifecycle** of software development for 4 projects with 100% on-time delivery while staying 5% under budget.

- Designed and developed product details page by using React for user interface, SASS, MUI, for styling, and Redux for state management.
- Participated in the development of API for payment between B2B, B2C, and C2C by using Express.
- Used **Git** version control for the source code management of the application.
- **Tech Stack**: React, Express, Node.js, Redux, MUI

Web Developer Intern / Forest Company (Hong Kong)

JUN 2015 - NOV 2016

- Designed the Web application layout and forms using **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, and **jQuery**.
- Wrote application-level code to perform **client-side validation** using jQuery and JavaScript.
- Handled all the client-side validations, slide show, hide and show controls, dropdown menus, and tab navigation using jQuery.
- Used SVN for version control and defect tracking.
- Worked on cross-browser compatibility issues and fix the bugs pertaining to various browsers.
- Pair programmed with 2 engineers, and reviewed team's code to provide additional perspective and catch previously missed errors.
- **Tech Stack**: HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, JavaScript, MySQL

Skills

- **Programming Language**: JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python
- Front End Programming Language: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, SASS
- Back End Programming Language: JavaScript, Python, PHP
- **Database Technology**: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Elasticsearch
- **Technology Stack**: MERN, React + Django, React + Laravel, AWS, Firebase.
- Framework & Tool: React, Laravel, Express, Django, Initia.js, Git, Node.js
- **OS**: Mac / Linux / Windows / Unix
- **Development Methodologies**: SCRUM, Agile, Waterfall
- **Soft Skills:** Problem-solving, Critical thinking, Communication, Teamwork

Education

MAY 2015

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering / Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

GPA: 3.7

Certifications

- HTML5 Web Developer Camp Certificate
- Full Stack Web and Multiplatform App Development Certificate